

CONTACT INFO



+92-3327393496



faisalsaeedawan 20@gmail.com



https://faisalawan11.github.io/Portfolio/



https://www.linkedin.com/in/faisal-saeed-02334bab/

#### **EXPERTISE**

- Verilog/System verilog
- Universal Verification
   Methodology(UVM)
- Linux scripting

#### SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Verilator
- Questasim

#### CERTIFICATION

Chip Design Verification
 Essentials training certification
 from NUST University

# FAISAL SAEED

### DIGITAL DESIGN ENGINEER

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Digital Design Engineer specialized in RTL design and verification methodologies. Actively contributes to advanced System-on-Chip (SoC) designs, integrating technologies like AMBA protocols, with a future orientation toward DDR memory, controller, and DDR PHY. Meticulous attention to detail and commitment to excellence ensure high-performance designs.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## TRAINEE ENGINEER COMIRA SOLUTIONS

OCT 2022- MAR 2023

- Developed strong experties in Verilog HDL for efficient hardware design and verification, employing best practices with industry standards
- Developed a UVM testbench for integrating an ALU and synchronous FIFO modules

#### Design Engineer CoMIRA SOLUTIONS

APR 2023- PRESENT

- Collaborating with CoMira team on SoC development
- Working on LaTex for the documentation of SoC
- Writing C++ testbench for SoC development. This includes generating test cases, applying stimuli, and checking the expected outputs

#### **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR IN INDUSTRIAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING
NED UNIVERSITY | 2011–2015

MASTERS IN ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING

GHULAM ISHAQ KHAN INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING SCIENCES AND TECHNOLOGY | 2020-2023